## Timothy-Jacob Miyenseigha Marvellous

Software Engineer | Frontend Developer | Developer Advocate | UI/UX Designer | Network Technician | Cybersecurity Analyst | IT Support

Nigeria https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothy-jacob-

miyenseigha-634620215

**Bē** https://www.behance.net/timothymarvell2 ★ https://twitter.com/jtcontrolla

## **Profile**

Experienced Developer, I specialize in software development, frontend design, UI/UX Design, graphic design, and cybersecurity. I'm known for creating efficient, user-friendly applications and websites with visually captivating interfaces. My cybersecurity expertise ensures digital security through vulnerability identification and robust security measures. Committed to continuous learning, I'm ready for new tech challenges.

## **Professional Experience**

New York, USA GaoTek Inc | Remote

As a UI/UX Designer at GAO Tek Inc., responsible for designing intuitive and user-friendly interfaces for tech products. Tasks include conducting user research, wireframing, prototyping, and collaborating with developers to ensure seamless user

experiences across digital platforms.

2024/04 – 2024/09 UI/UX Designer London, England Aplentify | Remote

I create intuitive and visually appealing user interfaces, conduct user research, develop

personas, wireframe and prototype designs, and collaborate with cross-functional teams

to enhance user experiences. Proficient in Figma, Sketch, and photoshop.

2023/11 – 2024/10 **Front-End Developer & Graphic Designer** Bayelsa, Nigeria *Digitec Hub* 

Frontend Dev and Graphic design Instructor

Wrote clean and efficient HTML, CSS, JavaScript & React code.

2021/02 – 2023/11 Web Development

Delta, Nigeria Rolof Computer Academy ☑

Web development Instructor

Develop visually appealing, responsive websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Collaborate across teams to meet project needs.

Write clean, efficient code adhering to industry standards.

Support Receptionist/HR with strong social and communication skills.

2020/06 - 2020/09 **Network technician** 

Delta, Nigeria Nigeria National Petroleum Corporation NNPC | Internship

Configure, troubleshoot, and monitor network devices.

Perform routine maintenance, upgrades, and security audits.

Collaborate with teams to assess and address network needs.

## **Education**

2018 - 2023 **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering** 

Ado-Ekiti, Nigeria Afebabalola University, ABUAD

2011 - 2017High School Diploma, Science

Warri, Nigeria Edulyn College

**Skills** 

JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, HTML/CSS, BOOSTRAP,

tailwind CSS, and more

PHP, SQL, Python

Cyber Threat Management, Cybersecurity Analyst, Pen

Testing.

Hardware and System Maintenance

Receptionist/HR

Graphic Design, User interface design, UI/UX, Figma,

photoshop

Data Analyst

Strategic Thinking, Public Speaking and Communication, Team Management, Project

Management

Networking

Digital Marketing

Languages

• English • Creoles and pidgins, English-

based

French

Certificates

**Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering** 

Afebabalola University, 19th July, 2023

Junior Cybersecurity Analyst Career Path

Cisco Networking Academy, Sep 2023

Ethical Hacking Essentials (EHE)

EC-Council, Aug 2023

**Basic Certificate in Leadership Studies** 

Afebabalola University, May 2023

**Introduction to Cybersecurity** 

Cisco Networking Academy, Sep 2023

**Digital Marketing Certified** 

Hubspot 2024

**Foundations of Project Management** 

Google, Coursera March 2024

**Cyber Threat Management** 

Cisco Networking Academy, Sep 2023

Digital Forensic Essentials (DFE)

EC-Council, Aug 2023

Network Defense Essentials (NDE)

EC-Council, Aug 2023

Web Development

Rolof Computer Academy, Sep 2022

**Networking Basics** 

Cisco Networking Academy

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design

Google, Coursera April 2024

**Interests** 

• Playing Football

Cooking

• Traveling

• Learning/Reading

• Playing Video Game